Guide to the Cornell Plantations records, [ca. 1945]-1999
Cornell Plantations records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell Plantations records, [ca. 1945]-1999
34-4-2302
Cornell Plantations.
3.4 cubic ft., 215+ maps/drawings
Diaries, maps/charts, movie film, newspapers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Newspaper clippings, brochures, drawings for proposed buildings and gardens, journals and photographs. Oversized maps, plans and drawings. Also, videotape of the "The 150th Birthday Celebration of Beebe Lake," May 1, 1988.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Newspaper clippings, brochures, drawings for proposed buildings and gardens, and photographs. Also, videotape of the "The 150th Birthday Celebration of Beebe Lake," May 1, 1988.
Includes journals kept by gardeners from 1956-1999.
Now includes oversized maps and drawings of gardens and natural areas supervised by Cornell Plantations.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell Plantations.; Cornell University -- Description -- Views.
Places:
Cornell Plantations; Beebe Lake (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Videotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also the video A Journey Through Time and Nature, Cornell Plantations Path and Robert E. Jones Cornell Plantations papers, #34-4-4130.
SERIES LIST
Series I. General files and diaries
Boxes 1-4
Series II. Oversized plans, maps and drawings
Mapcase Folders 1-15
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. General files and diaries
  - Proposed arboretum maps, ca. 1935-1936 (Box 1)
  - General plans, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Farm of NYS College of Agriculture, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Survey of existing conditions, 1920 (Box 1)
  - General info, ca. 1950-1960 (Box 1)
  - "The 150th Birthday Celebration of Beebe Lake" (VHS tape), 1988; V-52 (Box 1)
  - Journals (date range is incomplete), 1956-1975 (Box 2)
  - Journals, 1976-1987 (Box 3)
  - Journals, 1988-1999 (Box 4)
- Series II. Oversized plans, maps and drawings
  - No. 1: Dept. of Buildings & Grounds, Cornell; Map of Grounds Cornell University, December 1936 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 2: [topographical map of part of the arboretum], n.d. (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 3: Location of proposed Arboretum Road; J.E.M., May 15, 1939 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 3a: [copy of No. 3], n.d. (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 4: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Agricultural Conservation Program; Farm Map, John Hornbrook; W.H. Parker, July 24, 1940 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 5: Area Reserved for Animal Husbandry as per Field Trip (Herman & McClinton), February 9, 1939 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 6: Proposed Berm - East of Bridge - S. Shore, n.d. (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 7: Topographical Map North of NYS Highway #392; J.E. Miller, September 26, 1939 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 8: [acetate "Test" of a layout, 76 26'15"], n.d. (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 9: Site Utilities, September 25, 1968 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 10: Cornell University; Map of Grounds; H.G.D. Jr., J.W.M., n.d. (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 11: Proposed Planting New Insectary; T.R.H., J.E.M., January 26, 1938 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 12: C.U.; Cascadilla Glen Development, Sackett Gift, n.d. (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 13: Test Holes, Wildflower Garden, n.d. (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 14: Arboretum Planting Plan, Test Garden; T.J.S., R.J.K. [very fragile], August 1949 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 15: Cornell Plantations; Pasture Lands of the Department of Animal Husbandry [topography], n.d. (Map-case Folder 1)
  - No. 16: C.U., Planning Office; Proposed Roadway, P4-2; D.W.G., kb [numbered in front, top right-hand corner], November 1, 1963 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 16a: [copy of 16 with pencil addition], n.d. (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 17: [copy of 16] P4 -3; D.W.G., A.T.E., November 1, 1963 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 18: C.U., Department of Buildings & Properties; Campus Maps 5745, 1967 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 19: Central Heating Plant [elevations]; Green and Wicks, April 1912(?) (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 20: [same as 19] Roof Plan and Cross Sections, n.d. (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 21: [same as 19] Elevations, n.d. (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 22: C.U.; Structural Steel Alterations to Agr. Col. Heating Plant, September 1926 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 23: C.U., The Campus of Cornell University [pencil additions], 1951 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 24: Campus Plan: Cornell University; J.N.T., September 1962 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 25: [same as 24] [pencil and colored pencil additions], n.d. (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 26: Campus Plan: Cornell University; J.N.T., November 1965 January 1967 September 1968 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 27: C.U., Dept. of Bldgs. & Grounds; Map of Grounds; H.G.D. Jr., J.W.H. [test garden, ericaceous area], n.d. (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 28: Areas of Special Interest to the Cornell Plantations, Kite Hill -Cascadilla Creek; J.E. Davison, April 20, 1964 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 29: C. U. Department of Design & Project Management; Water System Construction, Plantations; R.S.R., July 9, 1975 August 22, 1978 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 30: Department of the Interior, National Park Service (NPS) and Cornell University; Plan of Foot Trail "1a"; A.H.R., June 30, 1937 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - No. 30a: [copy of 30], June 30, 1937 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 31: NPS; Master Plan; N.M. Wells, June 29, 1938 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 31a: [same as 31] [color added to map], June 29, 1938 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 31b: [same as 31] [in addition to 31a this has a third approval date], June 29, 1938 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 32: NPS; Diagramatic Study for Arboretum; A.H. Reid, August 20, 1935 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 33: NPS; Cornell University Arboretum (CUA), Base Map; J.E. Miller [10"X16"], March 31, 1936 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 33a: [essentially same map as 33]; J.W. Humphreys, February 16, 1937 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 33b: [same as 33a with one added approval date], February 16, 1937 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 33c: [same as 33a with Game Farm pencilled in]; J. E. Miller, April 1937 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 33d: [same as 33a with "Location Plan for Planting" and some color added]; J. E. Miller, April 1937 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 33e: [copy of 33d], April 1937 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 34: CUA, Proposed Arboretum at Cornell University, Details of Plan Road "A", n.d. (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 34a: [same map as 34, different title] Standard Details for Road "A"; HE/?, November 1936 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 35: NPS; CUA, Plan of Foot Trail No. "la," 8+00 to 11+50; A.H.R., February 30, 1937 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 36: [same as 35] 11+50 to 16+70, February 30, 1937 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 37: [same as 35] 0-35 to 16+70, February 30, 1937 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 38: Gutter Frame & Grate Details; J.E. Miller, March 15, 1939 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 39: NPS; CUA, Layout Plan; N.M. Wells, February 24, 1939 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 39a: [same map as 39] [details and some color added], February 24, 1939 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 40: NPS; CUA, Drain to Supply Ponds; N.M. Wells, July 31, 1940 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 41: NPS; CUA, Plan for Spring Planting 1937; N.M.vi-A.H.R., April 21, 1937 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 42: NPS, CUA, Planting Plan Area 14, 7-1-38 to 6-30-39; N.M.Wells, 1938-1939 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 42a: [copy of 42], 1938-1939 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 43: NPS, CUA, Profile & Sections Truck Trail #1; J. E. Miller, June 7, 1937 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 43a: [copy of 43], June 7, 1937 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 44: NPS; CUA, Profile & Details, Rubble Masonry vlall & Riprap; J. E. Miller, August 8, 1939 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 45: NPS; CUA, Location Plan of Water Lines East of NYS Highway 392; J. E. Miller, July 1, 1936 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - No. 46: NPS; CUA, Profile of Storm Sewer Extension; J.E. Miller, June 22, 1936 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 47: NPS; CUA, Details for Dam - Cascadilla Creek East of ROTC Stables; J. E. Miller, May 8, 1937 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 48: NPS, CUA, Planting Plan Area 9 7-1-38 to 6-30-39; N.M. Wells, February 1, 1938 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 49: NPS; CUA, Planting Plan, Area 11, l0th Period; N.M. Wells, February 1, 1938 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 50: NPS; CUA, Plans Road "A"; also Section of Caldwell Road Proposed for Abandonment July 16, 1936; A.H.R. & L.T.C., March 4, 1936 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 51: NPS; CUA, Grading Plan Road "A"; N. M. Wells, March 29(?), 1937 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 52: CUA, Cross Section & Profile of Road "A"; A.H.R., March 20, 1937 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 53: NPS; CUA, Road "A" - Plan, Profile, Section & Construction Details; A.H.R., December 2, 1935 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 54: NPS; CUA, Details of Wall along Road "A"; A.H. Reid, November 11, 1936 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 55: NPS; CUA, Profile of Foot Trail through Slim Jim Woods - Path "A"; J.E. Miller, etc., December 20, 1938 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 56: NPS; CUA, Profile of Foot Trail through Slim Jim Woods, Paths "A" and "B"; J. E. Mill er, etc., December 20, 1938 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 57: NPS; CUA, Topographical Survey for Overlook; A.W. McElwee, August 1, 1935 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 58: CUA, Road "A" Profile Stations 36+00 to 54+00, n.d. (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 59: NPS; CUA, Grading Plan Road "A," Stations 31+50 to 33+00; N. M. Wells, March 20, 1937 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 60: NPS; CUA, [same as 59], Stations 32+50 to 36+00, N. M. Wells, March 20, 1937 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - No. 61: CUA, Plan Road "A," Stations 36+00 to 40+00, n.d. (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 62: CUA, Plan Road "A," Stations 40+00 to 42+50, n.d. (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 63: CUA, Plan Road "A," Stations 42+50 to 50+00, n.d. (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 64: CUA, Plan Road "A," Stations 50+00 to 54+00, n.d. (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 65: CUA, Plan Road "A," Stations 36+00 to 54+00, n.d. (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 66: NPS; CUA, Details for Stone Retaining Wall Service Road-Town Line; J.E.M., December 23, 1936 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 67: NPS; CUA, Service Road; A.W. Eustance, September 9, 1935 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 68: NPS; CUA, Service Road; A.W. Eustance, September 9, 1935 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 69: NPS; CUA, Prel. Drawings for Bridge Case. Cr. Town Line Road; J.E.M., January 4, 1937 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 70: NPS; CUA, Prel. Drawings for Bridge Case. Cr. Town Line Road; J.E.M., January 4, 1937 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 71: NPS; CUA; Bridge Details - Cascadilla Creek - Service Road - Town Line; J.E. Miller, January 14, 1937 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 72: Plan of South Abutment and Wing Halls; [this is the original, with empty blocks where the information is usually located], n.d. (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 72a: NPS; CUA, Bridge Details - Cascadilla Creek - Service Road - Town Line; J. E. Miller [finished copy of 72, information added], January 15, 1937 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 73: NPS; CUA, Bridge Details...; J. E. Miller, January 14, 1937 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 74: NPS; CUA, Gutter Service Road- Town Line; J. E. Miller, December 29, 1937 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 74a: [copy of 74], December 29, 1937 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 75: NPS; CUA, Plan of Road "A" and "A3"; N. M. Wells, December 9, 1937 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - No. 76: NPS; CUA, Plan Profile Road "A5"; N. M. Wells, September 20, 1938 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 76.1: Profile - Reinforced Concrete Culvert, Road "A5", November 1, 1938 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 77: NPS; CUA, Layout Plan: N. M. Wells [multicolored map, quite complete], January 27, 1940 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 78: Profile of Truck Trail (East End), February 7, 1939 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 79: Truck Trail, n.d. (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 80: CUA, Road "A" Sections, Stations 36+00 to 45+00, n.d. (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 81: CUA, Road "A" Sections, Stations 46+00 to 54+00 [Nos. 80 and 81 lack agency names, etc. but have the legend C.C.C. S. P.48 which also appears on almost all National Park Service maps.], n.d. (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 82: Profile of Path "3" and "3A" [has legend C.C.C.206 only, no other agency connection], n.d. (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 83: Cross Sections [identifying number is COR - 9071 -2-5), n.d. (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 84: Cro ss Sections [COR-9072-3-5], n.d. (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 85: Cross Sections [COR- 9079 -4-5], n.d. (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 86: Dept. of Ani aml Husbandry Pasture Lands; maps used: Aerial Photograph ARU-3N- 141, 10-25-54 and Dept. of Interior - State Park Division 2-NY-48-2058, 3-2-36, August 26, 1964 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 87: CUA, Plan for Overlook; N. M. Wells [Nelson M. Wells], November 5, 1935 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 88: Details of Log Dams and Docking; N. M. Wells, December 9, 1936 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No 89: CUA, General Grading Plan; Aug. 20, 1937 revised; N. M. Wells, October 23, 1937 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 90: CUA, Preliminary Plan for Region between North Entrance and Gardens, Plan No. 32-10; N. M. Wells, August 27, 1935 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - No. 91: CUA; General Planting Plan, Plan No. 32-41; Nelson M. Wells, October 20, 1936 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 91a: [copy of 91; a corner is missing], October 20, 1936 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 92: CUA Development, ca. 1936-1937 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 93: CUA, Overpass Bridge at Caldwell Road, Plan No. 32-27A, August 1935 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 94: CUA Overpass Bridge at Caldwell Road, Plan No. 32-27B, August 1935 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 95: CUA, General Planting Plan, Poplar Collection, Plan No. 32-64; September 16, 1937, revised Sept. 26, 1937, May 29, 1939 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 95a: [same map revised], October 15, 1939 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 96: CUA, Arboretum Entrance on Tower Road, Plan No. 32-69, October 4, 1937 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 97: CUA, Preliminary Plan for Special Gardens, Plan No. 32-60A, August 25, 1937 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 97a: [same map with additional pencil markings], August 25, 1937 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 98: Cornell University; A General Plan for the Cornell University Arboretum, Plan No. 32-71, February 1, 1938 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 98a: [same as 98], February 1, 1938 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 99: CUA, Study for Special Gardens, Plan No. 32-25; February 25, 1936 revised, April 16, 1936 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 100: CUA, Study for Special Gardens, Plan No. 32-25B, November 5, 1926 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 101: CUA, Study for Special Gardens, Plan No. 32- 25B; revised, May 15, 1937 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 102: CUA, Study for Special Gardens, Plan No. 32-25C, October 23, 1936 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 103: CUA, Study for Special Gardens, Plan No. 32-25D, November 4, 1936 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 104: CUA, Study for Special Gardens, Plan No. 32-25E, August 22, 1938 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 105: CUA, Study for Special Gardens, Plan No. 32-25F, September 5, 1938 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 106: CUA, Study for Special Gardens, Plan No. 32-25G, September 14, 1938 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 107: CUA, Road in Cascadilla Valley, Plan No. 32-84, February 3, 1939 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 108: CUA, Road in Cascadilla Valley, Plan No. 32-84A, May 20, 1930 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 109: CUA, Road in Cascadilla Valley, Plan No. 32-84B, August 1, 1939 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 110: CUA, Study for Hedge Garden. Plan No. 32-87A, April 14, 1939 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 110a: [copy of 110, on tracing paper], April 14, 1939 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - No. 111: CUA, Study for Hedge Garden, Plan No. 32-878, April 14, 1939 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 111a: [copy of 111, on tracing paper], April 14, 1939 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 112: CUA, Diagram for Planting at Bridge, Plan No. 32-73, April 18, 1938 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 113: CUA; Planting Plan Pine and American Willow Collection, Plan No. 32-78; Sept. 26, 1938 revised Nov. 29, 1938, May 29, 1939, October 15, 1939 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 114: CUA, Planting Plan for Juniper Collection (to supersede Plan No. 32-32), Plan No. 32-82, November 15, 1938 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 114a: [copy of 114 with two ok signatures], 1939 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 115: CUA, Cascadilla Valley near Judd Falls Road, Plan No. 32-92; May 29, 1939 revised, August 5, 1939 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 116: CUA, General Development Plan, West End of Pea Collection, Plan No. 93A, June 12, 1939 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 116a: [revision of 116; Sept. 26, 1939], November 15, 1939 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 116b. [copy of 116a with some added notation], November 15, 1939 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 117: CUA, General Development Plan, East Portion of Pea Collection, Plan No. 32-938, June 12, 1939 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 117a: [revision of 117], November 15, 1939 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 117b: [revision of 117, Nov. 15, 1939], May 1, 1940 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 118: CUA, Portion of Spruce Collection (supersedes Plan 32-38); Plan No. 32-97, August 5, 1939 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 119: CUA; Planting Plan West Porton of Pea Collection, Plan No. 32-101A; November 15, 1939 revised, April 15, 1940 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 120: CUA; Planting Plan East Portion of Pea Collection, Plan No. 32-101B, November 15, 1939 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 121: CUA, Planting Plan for Gardens of Pea Collection, Plan No. 32- 102; November 20, 1939 revised, April 5, 1940 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 122: CUA, General Study Plan for the Valley of Fall Creek; Plan No. 32-118, July 20, 1940 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 122a: [same map as 122 with added color and pencil notations], July 20, 1940 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 123: CUA, Diagram of Roads in Vicinity of Town Line, Plan No. 32-119, August 1, 1940 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 123a: [copy of 123 with added notation], August 1, 1940 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 124: CUA, Foliage Study in Forest Home Valley, Plan 21-133, March 25, 1941 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 125: Proposed Arboretum, Cornell University [fragile], February 20, 1928 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 125a: [same as 125, fragile], February 20, 1928 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 125b: Proposed Arboretum, Cornell University, 2-20-28, revised 12-2-33, latest general development plan; ? W.S. [fragile], January 27, 1935 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - No. 126: NPS; CUA Grading Plan; J. E. Miller [fragile], n.d. (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 127: Study of Water Lines North of Slim Jim Woods [fragile], February 25, 1938 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 128: Underground Water Sanitation Fuel Lines [very fragile], n.d. (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 129: C.U. Dept. of Military Science and Tactics; Cornell University and Vicinity from Surveys 1908- 1913. [Printed copy with pencil notations; fragile], 1908-1913 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 130: Arboretum, C.R. W.E .S.; 1969; Dick Mc, March 1970 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 131: C.U.; Arboretum Planting Plan, Test Garden Area; C.R. C.F.W.S, December 17, 1934 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 132: Cornell University Vine and Shrub Garden; Schuyler Reid Hafely, March 28, 1935 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 133: The Cornell Plantations; reproduced from U.S.G.S. work map of 1949; J.D.H., January 1968 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 134: Cornell Plantations; Plant Locations; Sheet 1 of 3; J. Shauger, March 1976 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 134a: Cornell Plantations; Plant Locations; Sheet 1 of 3; J. Shauger [additional plant names pencilled in], March 1976 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 135: Cornell Plantations; Plant Locations; Sheet 2 of 3; J. Shauger [additional plant names pencilled in], March 1976 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 135a: Cornell Plantations; Plant Locations; Sheet 2 of 3; J. Shauger (refined version of 135), March 1976 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 136: Cornell Plantations; Plant Locations; Sheet 3 of 3; J. Shauger, March 1976 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 136a: Cornell Plantations; Plant Locations; Sheet 3 of 3 (refined version of 136), March 1976 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 137: Comstock Knoll; Matthew L. Biscotti, May 30, 1967 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 137a: [same map], n.d. (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 137b: [same map on tracing paper with list of 39 specimens of Thuja], n.d. (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 138: CUA; Location Plan Taxaceae; R.S.B. J.F.C., n.d. (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 139: Cornell Plantations; Oak-Taxus Area; J.S.K., October 1976 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 140: Cornell Plantations; Mundy Wildflower Garden [numbered in lower right hand corner (back)], May 1976 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - No. 141: Cornell Plantations; Shrub Garden; Ann B. Paschal, March 1978 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 142: Gymnosperm Slope - 1; J.S.K., June 6, 1976 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 143: Cornell Plantations; Viburnum Collection; C. W. Cares [on tracing paper], August 1959 (Map-case folder 10)
  - No. 143a: [copy of 143 with additions], n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 143b: [refined copy of 143a], n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 144: CUA; Chamaecyparis, Thuja, Tsuga, n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 144a: [same as 144], n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 145: CUA; Pinaceae; R.S.B. J.F.C., n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 146: CUA; Pinaceae; R.S.B. J.F.C. [different from 145], n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 147: Cornell Plantations; Ground Cover Collections; Jeryl Shauger, April 1, 1976 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 148: Cornell University Test Gardens; Lilac Collection; C.W. Cares [on tracing paper], April 21, 1959 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 148a: [copy of 148], April 21, 1959 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 149: Cornell Plantations; Leon B. Allen Trail - Sculpture Garden - Test Garden; Jeryl Shauger, March 1976 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 149a: [copy of 149 with refinements], March 1976 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 150: Cornell University Dept. of Bldgs. and Props.; Map E5786-4 Tree Peonies [pencilled in]; Hartman, November 25, 1975 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 151: The Cornell Arboretum Located in the Geographic Center of the Nursery Interests, n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 151a: [same as 151 with some additions; Nelson M. Wells], n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 152: Monkey Run research Area Loaned to the Depts. of Plant Pathology, Entomology and Limnology by Cornell Plantations, June 10, 1964 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 152a: [same as 152], June 10, 1964 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 153: Cornell Plantations; Naturalistic Garden; J. Shauger, January 8, 1976 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 154: Cornell Plantations; Self Guiding Tour, n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 155: Dwarf Garden; renovated; d.c.schaaf, October 1964 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 155a: [same as 155 with plant names added], October 1964 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 155b: [same as 155 with different plant names added], October 1964 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 156: Synoptic Shrub Collection, Sheet No. 1 part A, P. G. Mower, n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 156a: Sheet No. 1 part B, n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 157: Synoptic Shrub Collection, Sheet No. 2 [2 parts stapled together]; Mower & Vrugtmann, 1966 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 158: Cornell Plantations; Synoptic Garden; R. G. Mower, July 1966 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 159: Synoptic Shrub Collection Base Map, Sheet 2 of 3, n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 159: Synoptic Shrub Collection Base Map, Sheet 3 of 3, n.d. (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 160: Lands administered by the N.Y. State College of Agriculture; prepared by J. F. Cornman with R. H. Wheeler, July 7, 1951 (Map-case Folder 10)
  - No. 161: Cornell Plantations; Trillium Collection; Ina Vrugtman, November 1965 (Map-case Folder 11)
  - No. 162: Cornell Plantations; Map prepared for Model of Pasture Lands; Ina Vrugtman, Spirng 1966 (Map-case Folder 11)
  - No. 162a: [copy of 162], Spring 1966 (Map-case Folder 11)
  - No. 163: Cornell Plantations, Nut Tree Survey; W.E.S., March 1970 (Map-case Folder 11)
  - No. 164: Comstock Knoll, n.d. (Map-case Folder 11)